Vonnegut mss., 1941-2007 LMC 1860
Lilly Library
- II. Writings (Box 3)
  - Short Stories and Articles (Box 12)
    - Evil Companions. (page 1 only)(unpublished) (Box 13)
    - Explosion in a Putty Factory. (see: The Humbugs) (Box 13)
    - Father of the Man. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - The Finders. (idea only) (Box 13)
    - First Command. (see: Fubar) (Box 13)
    - Forbidden Fruit. (see: Fubar) (Box 13)
    - Form 572. (see: Fubar) (Box 13)
    - The Foster Portfolio. Collier's Sept. 8, 1951 (Box 13)
    - Fountain of Youth. (incomplete) (Box 13)
    - Four Utterly Honest People (Box 13)
    - Fubar. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - Gas. (see: The Man Without No Kiddleys) (Box 13)
    - The Genius Club. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - Girl Pool. (unpublished) (see also: Major works: Girl Pool) (Box 13)
    - Go Back to Your Precious Wife and Son. Ladies Home Journal. Feb. 1, 1962 (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 13)
    - God's Gift to the Women. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - Gongs On In Blg 226. (see: Noodess Collny) (Box 13)
    - The Good Explainer. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - Great Day. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - The Great Integrator. (see: Eternal Good Taste) (Box 13)
    - The Great WJZM Conspiracy. (incomplete) (Box 13)
    - Grieve My Lord No More (Box 13)
    - Guardian of the Person. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - Guns Before Butter. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - Hal Irwin's Magic Lamp. Cosmopolitan Jan. 7, 1957 (Box 13)
    - Hall of Mirrors. (unpublished) Includes correspondence with Ken Littauer, 1961 (Box 13)
    - Happy Birthday. (unpublished), 1951 (Box 13)
    - Harrison Bergeron. Fantasy and Science Fiction Oct 1961 (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 13)
    - Hayden's Hedgehog. (see: War Story) (Box 13)
    - The Heavenly Athletes. (two pages only) (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - Hello, Red (Box 13)
    - High Papooli on the Sherezade. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - Honeybug. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - The Honor of a Newsboy. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - Hotbox. (see: With His Hand on the Throttle) (Box 13)
    - Houseparty. (see: Any Reasonable Offer) (Box 13)
    - How to Write With Style. (advertisement for International Paper Company)., Apr. 30, 1980 (Box 13)
    - The Humbugs. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - Hundred Dollar Kisses. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - The Hyannis Port Story. Saturday Evening Post Nov. 14, 1963 (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 13)
    - Hyannis Port to West Palm, The Log of an Ordinary Seaman Aboard the Kennedy Yacht "Marlin," on a Voyage Down the Inland Waterway. (see: The Inland Waterway) (Box 13)
    - I Don't Feel Any Different. (see: Guardian of the Person) (Box 13)
    - I-Don't-Know-What-It-Is and Eve. (see: Runaways) (Box 13)
    - I Grasp Your Hand. (see: The Manned Missiles) (Box 13)
    - I Shall Not Want (Box 13)
    - I Used to Work in Chicago. (see: Easy Go) (Box 13)
    - The Ice Man and the Rose. (incomplete) (Box 13)
    - Ice 9 (Box 13)
    - If Sherman's Horse Can Take It. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - The Inland Waterway. Venutre Jan. 22, 1965 (Box 13)
    - The Island. (incomplete) (Box 13)
    - [Jackson Pollock] (Box 13)
    - Jazz in Czechoslovakia., 1986 (Box 13)
    - Jenny. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - Julio-O. (see: King Mouso Is Dead) (Box 13)
    - Just You and Me, Sammy. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - King and Queen of the Universe. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - King Mouso Is Dead. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - King of the Hill. (see: A Night For Love) (Box 13)
    - The Krummbein Portfolio. (see: Custom Made Bride) (Box 13)
    - Land of Opportunity. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - The Last Customer. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - The Last High Papouli. (see: High Papooli on the Sheherazade) (Box 14)
    - The Lie. Saturday Evening Post Feb. 24, 1962 (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 14)
    - Little Drops of Water. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Live Happily Ever After. (see: Powder Blue Dragon) (Box 14)
    - A Locomotive Named Spitfire. (see: With His Hand on the Throttle) (Box 14)
    - A Long, Long Way From Home. (see: Land of Opportunity) (Box 14)
    - Long Walk to Forever. Ladies Home Journal Aug. 1960 (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 14)
    - Look at the Birdie. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Love in the Daytime. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - M.R.A. (story notes) (Box 14)
    - Mad Annie (Box 14)
    - [Making Peace with Dying Father (unpublished)] (Box 14)
    - The Man with no Kiddleys. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - The Manned Missiles. Cosmopolitan July, 1958 (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 14)
    - Manny. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Merle Pfitzer. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - [Minister and Message] (unpublished)---incomplete (Box 14)
    - Miss Snow, You're Fired. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Miss Temptation. Saturday Evening Post Apr. 21, 1956 (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 14)
    - Mnemonics. Collier's Apr. 28, 1951 (Box 14)
    - Money Talks. (see also: Major works: Money Talks) (Box 14)
    - Moonshine. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - More Stately Mansions. Collier's Dec. 22, 1951 (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 14)
    - The More Vivid, the Better. (see: Mnemonics) (Box 14)
    - A Mouldy Catcher's Mitt, A Leaky Showerhead, and Thou. (see: Fubar) (Box 14)
    - Mr. Ambassador. (page 1 only) (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Mr. Z. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Mrs. Jacobin. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - [My Fair Lady (unpublished)---incomplete] (Box 14)
    - My Heart in My Hands. (see: Four Utterly Honest People) (Box 14)
    - My Name is Everyone. (see: Who Am I This Time) (Box 14)
    - My Visit to Hell. Parade Jan. 7, 1990 (Box 14)
    - New Moons. (see: The Manned Missiles) (Box 14)
    - Next Door. Cosmopolitan Apr. 1955 (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 14)
    - The Nice Little People. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - A Night For Love. Saturday Evening Post Nov. 23, 1967 (Box 14)
    - Noodess Collny. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - The No-Talent Kid. Saturday Evening Post Oct. 25, 1962 (Box 14)
    - One Dead Puritan. (see: Miss Temptation) (Box 14)
    - One Hot Night in Cuba. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - 120 M.P.H. Guaranteed (see: Powder Blue Dragon) (Box 14)
    - $100 a Day. (see: The Foster Portfolio) (Box 14)
    - One Very Stale Cigar. (see: The Man Without No Kiddleys) (Box 14)
    - Out, Brief Candle. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Out in All That Moonlight. (see: A Night For Love) (Box 14)
    - The Package. Collier's July 26, 1952 (Box 14)
    - Paris, France. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - The Paper Sale. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Parts Unknown. (see: Return to Salerno) (Box 14)
    - The Pete Parry Murder. (story idea only) (Box 14)
    - The Petrified Ants. (see: The Ants of Erz Gebirge) (Box 14)
    - The Pipe City Blues. Collier's Sept. 1961 (Box 14)
    - The Pit (Box 14)
    - Pity the Poor Alewives. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Please Omit Flowers. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Poko (Box 14)
    - The Poontangishads. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Poor Little Rich Town. Collier's Oct. 25, 1952 (Box 14)
    - Poupan (Box 14)
    - The Powder Blue Dragon. Cosmopolitan Nov. 1954 (Box 14)
    - The Poisoner. (unpublished?) (Box 14)
    - The Queen Bee. (see: Manny) (Box 14)
    - Report on the Barnhouse Effect. (Welcome to the Monkey House) (see also: Major works: Report on the Barnhouse Effect) (Box 14)
    - Requiem for Zeitgeist. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Return to Salerno. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Robotville and Mr. Caslow. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Rome. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Runaways. Saturday Evening Post Apr. 15, 1961 (Box 14)
    - Ruth. (unpublished) (Box 14)
    - Saint Big Nick. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Sally in the Garden. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Seventeen Again. (unpublished--incomplete) (Box 15)
    - Shelter-Hopping. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Shout About it from the Housetops. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Sinbad. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Skyscraper National Park. Architectural Digest 1987 (Box 15)
    - Slavery. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Slice of Life. (unpublished) (see also: Major works: Slice of Life) (Box 15)
    - Slightly Salty. (unpublished--incomplete) (Box 15)
    - Something Borrowed. (see also: Major works: Happy Birthday, Wanda June) (Box 15)
    - Something Magic About Me. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - A Song for Selma. (unpublished; Vonnegut correspondence) (Box 15)
    - Souvenir. Argosy Dec. 1952 (Box 15)
    - Spit and Image. (incomplete and unpublished; see: Introduction to Jailbird) (Box 15)
    - Spoils. (unpublished; New Republic contest entry) (Box 15)
    - Steady as She Goes. (see: High Papooli on the Sheherazade) (Box 15)
    - Sucker's Portfolio (Box 15)
    - The Sultan's Sons. (see: The Humbugs) (Box 15)
    - Sweet Adeline. (see: Bevo) (Box 15)
    - Sweet Revenge. (see: To the Victor) (Box 15)
    - T.L.C. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Tango. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Target of Opportunity. (page 1 only) (Box 15)
    - Ten Nights in a Ballroom. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - $10,000 a Year, Easy. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Thanasphere. Collier's Feb. 1950 (Box 15)
    - Thanks Just the Same. (see: This Son of Mine) (Box 15)
    - They're Everywhere You Look! (incomplete) (Box 15)
    - This Little Piggy. (see: Jenny) (Box 15)
    - This Son of Mine. Saturday Evening Post Aug. 18, 1956 (Box 15)
    - Ticklish. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Time and Motion Study. (see: Poor Little Rich Town) (Box 15)
    - Time For One More. (see: Guardian of the Person) (Box 15)
    - Time The Present. (see: Moonshine) (Box 15)
    - 2 B R 0 2 B. If Jan. 1962 (Box 15)
    - To the Victor. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Tom Edison's Shaggy Dog. Collier's Mar. 14, 1953 (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 15)
    - Tomorrow and Tomorrow and Tomorrow. (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 15)
    - Tovrov. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - A Trip to the Doctor. (see: The Good Explainer) (Box 15)
    - Triple Armor. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Twins. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - The Twister. (unpublished - story idea only) (Box 15)
    - The Unicorn Trap. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Unknown Soldier. with a rejection letter from Cosmopolitan 1992 (Box 15)
    - Unpaid Consultant. Cosmopolitan Mar. 1955 (Box 15)
    - Unready to Wear. Galaxy Apr. 1953 ( as: The Amphibians; Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 15)
    - Up-Beat. (see: The No-Talent Kid) (Box 15)
    - Varga Girls. Esquire 1987? (Box 15)
    - Vetorino. (unpublished, story idea only) (Box 15)
    - Wailing Shall Be in All Streets. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Walnut Versus Something Light. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - War Story. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - War Zone. Parade Jan. 7, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Western Style Meditation. (Essay for "Kroch's and Brentano's") (Box 15)
    - Where There Are No Laws. (see: The Manned Missiles) (Box 15)
    - While Mortals Sleep. (see: Christmas Contest) (Box 15)
    - White King. Collier's Nov. 10, 1950 (Box 15)
    - Who Am I This Time. Saturday Evening Post Dec. 16, 1961 as My Name Is Everyone (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 15)
    - Who Says It's a Parade? (see: Robotville and Mr. Caslow) (Box 15)
    - Why I Am Funny and Original. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - The Widow Koradubian. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - With His Hand on the Throttle. (unpublished) (Box 15)
    - Yeh, Mabel (Box 15)
  - Speeches (Box 16)
    - At Mark Twain's House, Hartford, CT, 1979, Apr. 13 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Eugene V. Debs Award acceptance, 1981, Nov. 7 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Saint John the Divine, New York City, 1982, May 23 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - War Preparers Anonymous. YM-YWHA, New York City and printed in The Nation, 1983, May (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - At Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1980, Oct. 22 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Ware Lecture, Unitarian-Universalist Association, Rochester, NY, 1986, June 26 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - To American Psychiatric Association, 1988, Oct. 5 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Congressional Arts Caucus, New York Historical Society, 1990, Mar. 31 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Notes for various speeches, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - On steps of Lowe Library at Columbia on the Gulf War, 1991, Jan. 14 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Paul Engle Memorial service, 1991, Apr. 14 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Jerzy Kosinski tribute, 1991, Oct. 7 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Untitled, given at Yale?, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - American Humanist Association, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Fiftieth anniversary of the bombing of Hiroshima. For Coalition for New Priorities, Chicago, IL, 1995, Aug. 6 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Memorial service for Terry Southern, All Souls Unitarian Church, NYC, 1995, Dec. 9 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Introduction to reading by John Irving at 92nd St. YMHA, 1996, Mar. 11 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Tribute to former student Loree Rackstraw to be read at party celebrating her retirement from the University of N. Iowa, 1996, May 10 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Graduation speech, Butler University, 1996, May 11 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Tribute to poet William Meredith, Connecticut College, 1996, Oct. 4 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - At the Athenaeum, Indianapolis, 1996, Oct. 10 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - [Censorship], undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Richard Yates Memorial, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
- III. Farber Files (Box 16)
  Contain the files of Donald C. Farber in his capacity as Vonnegut's lawyer and literary agent. Arranged alphabetically by work. Includes: correspondence, contracts, notes, and other materials. The correspondence includes requests to publish, translate, or produce on stage or film various works. "Notes" refers to Farber's and his secretaries' handwritten notes. (See also: I. General correspondence)
  - Between Time and Timbuktu. Correspondence: notes, 1971-1992 (Box 16, Folder 24-26)
  - Bluebeard. Correspondence: notes, 1986-1992 (Box 16, Folder 27-29)
  - Breakfast of Champions. Correspondence: contracts; notes; promotional material, 1972-1995 (Box 16, Folder 30-36)
  - Cat's Cradle. Correspondence: contracts; notes, 1970-1995 (Box 16, Folder 37-40)
  - Deadeye Dick. Correspondence: notes; promotional materials, 1981-1995 (Box 16, Folder 41-43)
  - Fates Worse Than Death. Correspondence: notes, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 44-45)
  - Galapagos. Correspondence: notes, 1982-1994 (Box 16, Folder 46-48)
  - God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater (Box 16, Folder 46-48)
    - Correspondence: contracts, 1975-1992 (Box 16, Folder 49-54)
    - Notes; promotional materials and playbill; Rosewater Partnership (Box 17, Folder 1-5)
  - Happy Birthday, Wanda June. Correspondence: contracts; notes; programs, poster, set plan & property plot, 1970-1994 (Box 17, Folder 6-21)
  - Hocus Pocus. Correspondence: notes; publicity schedule, 1986-1995 (Box 17, Folder 22-26)
  - Jailbird. Correspondence: contracts, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 27-28)
  - Make Up Your Mind. Correspondence: contracts; notes; programs, 1985-1991 (Box 17, Folder 29-33)
  - Mother Night (Box 17, Folder 29-33)
    - Correspondence: contracts, 1959-1994 (Box 17, Folder 33-40)
    - Contracts (cont.); notes (Box 18, Folder 1-5)
  - Nice, Nice, Very Nice. Correspondence:contracts, 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
  - Palm Sunday. Correspondence: contracts; notes, 1980-1991 (Box 18, Folder 8-10)
  - Player Piano. Correspondence: contracts, 1970-1992 (Box 18, Folder 11-12)
  - Rage and Outrage. Correspondence: contracts; notes; story outlines, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 13-16)
  - The Sirens of Titan. Correspondence: contracts; notes; programs, 1971-1991 (Box 18, Folder 17-22)
  - Slapstick. Correspondence: contracts, 1976-1988 (Box 18, Folder 23-24)
  - Slaughterhouse Five. Correspondence: contracts; movie press kit; notes, 1967-1995 (Box 18, Folder 25-36)
  - Wampeters, Foma, and Grandfalloons. Correspondence:contracts; notes, 1969-1995 (Box 18, Folder 37-42)
  - Welcome to the Monkey House (Box 18, Folder 37-42)
    - Correspondence:, 1957-1971 (Box 18, Folder 43-44)
    - Correspondence: contracts; D.P. tear-sheet; notes; TV series - cast and crew lists, 1972-1995 (Box 19, Folder 1-36)
- IV. Publishing Records (Box 20)
  - Materials concerning contract negotiations and foreign publication rights, miscellaneous contracts, and royalty reports (Box 20)
- V. Miscellaneous (Box 21)
  - Biographical (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
    Includes: "An account of the ancestry of Kurt Vonnegut, Jr. by an ancient friend of his family, Indianapolis, 1970 "; passports; clippings; copies of entries to various biographical sources
  - Adams, James C., Jr (Box 21, Folder 3)
    "Thirteen haiku composed by James C. Adams, Jr., for the seventieth birthday of his uncle Kurt Vonnegut, Jr., November 11th, 1992 ..."
  - Artwork (Box 21, Folder 4-6)
    Includes: several original drawings by Vonnegut, catalog of his work, articles about his artwork, materials concerning an exhibition at the Margo Feiden Galleries in New York; two drawings of Vonnegut signed "GR81" (probably drawn from photographs).
  - Certificate of birth (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Two copies and associated materials
  - Conference Speakers International, Inc (Box 21, Folder 8)
    (later: Cosby Bureau International). Includes materials pertaining to speaking engagements
  - GHQ (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Description, rules, correspondence, and diagrams in Vonnegut's hand for the boardgame G.H.Q. (General Headquarters) invented by Vonnegut. With the original typed draft of a letter to Mr. Saalfield at Saalfield Game Company in Ohio
  - Jane's Book (Box 21, Folder 10)
    Typescript, over 100 pages. Part of a novel by Vonnegut's ex-wife, Jane Cox
  - The Public Concern Foundation, Inc (Box 21, Folder 11)
    List of Board of Directors, November 1988
  - School Material (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Photocopy of Vonnegut's final high school report card and history of PS43. Both enclosed in letter from Robert Weide at "Whyaduck Productions" to Vonnegut, May 18, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Anthropology 220, 230, 345, 499 and unidentified classes. Worksheets, notes and papers with notes and doodles throughout; notes, assignments, and charts; papers and exams, some with teacher's comments and grades. (Box 21, Folder 13-20)
    - History 201. Syllabus and Problems. University of Chicago Bookstore, June 1945. 153 pages. Vonnegut's college textbook, with his annotations and doodles. Various related pages laid in (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Political Science 256. Notes with doodles (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Thesis, tentatively titled "Mythologies of North American Nativistic Movements." Removed from binder. Summer, 1947. Notes, charts, annotated pages, with doodles throughout. Laid in are a couple of notes from his advisor and an outline for the project (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Thesis "Fluctuations Between Good and Ill Fortune in Simple Tales" written at the Writer's Workshop at University of Iowa. Four copies, October, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 24-25)
  - Screen Actors Guild (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Materials relating to membership
  - Tax materials (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
    paid bills, investment information, life insurance, retirement trust, etc.
  - Travel (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
    ephemera, including maps, Vonnegut's handwritten itineraries and schedules, tickets, visas, etc
  - Vonnegut, Alex (Box 22, Folder 6)
    (KV's uncle). Letter to Alex from Vonnegut, Nov. 28, 1947 accompanied by anecdote about it written by Vonnegut
  - Vonnegut, Bernard, Apr. 25, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    (KV's brother). Material relating to his death, Apr. 25, 1997
  - Vonnegut, Mark (Box 22, Folder 8)
    (KV's son). Color photocopy of painting with description of why he paints
  - Writer's Guild of America (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Photographs (Box 22, Folder 10)
    Copies of family pictures (9); Vonnegut, et al. taken at breakfast at Gracie Mansion honoring President Vaclav Havel of Czechoslovakia, 1990; Vonnegut taken at United Jewish Appeal-Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York, 1986; scrapbook: photographs taken at Vonnegut's 60th birthday celebration, Nov. 11, 1982; Bound volume: photographs taken in Prague, 1985; Scrapbook: "Vonneguts (from Aunt Raye's Scrapbook)," mostly clippings, a few photographs(see also: Box 23)
  - Miscellany (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Clippings (Box 22, Folder 12-31)
    Mostly reviews of Vonnegut's books and some about him
  - Printed (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Awards and degrees (Box 23)
    Drama Desk Award, 1970-1971; Grammy Award nomination, 1973; The John Steinbeck Award, 1992; Man of the Year award from General Electric; recognition from Indiana Arts Commission, The New School, Phi Beta Kappa, and The American Civil Liberties Union; honorary degrees from Hobart and William Smith Colleges, University of Rhode Island, and University of Chicago, University of Evansville; Television-Radio Writers' Annual Award, Writers Guild of America for "Auf Wiedersehen, 1957-1958 (see also: Box 26)
  - Awards and degrees (Box 31)
    Trophies: Distinguished Artist Award, North Shore Community Arts Center, Great Neck, NY 1977; Best Science Fiction Film, 1972, Slaughterhouse Five; International Poetry Forum, 11-17-71; Friends of the Chicago Library, Freedom to Read Award Presented by Christie Hefner, Dec. 4, 1982; Annual Playboy Editorial Award, 1976; ILLOWA Library Association, 1989 Intellectual Freedom Award.
  - Calendar (Box 23)
    The Freethinker's Calendar, 1989. Vonnegut's birthday noted on Nov. 11
  - Photograph of Vonnegut (Box 23)
  - Scrapbook (Box 23)
    photographs taken at Butler University, honorary degree presentation, May 11, 1996
  - Vonnegut, Kurt, Sr (Box 23)
    Senior Portfolio, 1908, M.I.T. (yearbook)
  - Audio cassettes: (Box 24)
    - Aunt Irma V. Lindener, interview with KV, Jr. Side 2: Aunt Irma and Richy, May 3, 1984 (Box 24)
    - Grana/Vonnegut Requiem., (Four tapes) (Box 24)
    - Jazz Section Interview - NPR., A concert and series of press conferences organized to bring attention the plight of the Jazz Section and it's struggle for cultural freedom in Czechoslovakia, International Jazz Coalition (Box 24)
    - The players pipe night in honor of Irwin Shaw, Oct. 7, 1979 (Box 24)
    - [God Bless You, Mr.] Rosewater, First Preview, Sept. 1979; (Two tapes) (Box 24)
    - Vonnegut on Republican Convention, 1980 (Box 24)
    - Side A: Vonnegut AMF Bluebeard. Side B: Vonnegut NPR ME Feature, Dec. 20, 1987 (Box 24)
    - Cambridge Forum: I call that mind free "The dignity of human nature", 1980 (Box 24)
    - Voices of freedom, (Two tapes) (Box 24)
  - VHS tapes: (Box 24)
    - Kurt Vonnegut Show at the 1/1 A Gallery in Denver, Colorado, Sept. 7-18, 1996 (Box 24)
    - Donahue Show. Is the pen mightier than the Ayatollah. Letter from Marlo Thomas taped to box, undated. (Box 24)
    - Our Father. Seven episodes from just outside the pearly gates. Dir: Michael Cumming, 1987 (Box 24)
    - CBS News Nightwatch interview, 2/10/86 (Box 24)
    - CBS News Nightwatch w/Charlie Rose, March 16-17, 1989 (Box 24)
  - Color slides of two pages each of manuscripts: Slaughterhouse Five and Breakfast of Champions (Box 24)
  - 4x5 transparencies: (Box 24)
    - Kurt Vonnegut art show, NYC, Margo Feiden Gallery(51), Oct. 10-Nov. 15, 1980 (Box 24)
    - Kurt's paintings (57) (Box 24)
- VI. Additions
  Contains materials received since 2002. Arranged in the same order as Series I through V.
  - Correspondence. (Box 26)
    Arrangement
    Arranged chronologically. Not indexed.
    - 1952-2007 (Box 26)
  - Writings - major works. (Box 26)
    Arranged alphabetically by title
    - God Bless you, Mr. Rosewater: A New Musical, by Howard Ashman, Alan Menken, and Dennis Green. Typescript, undated (Box 26)